<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Everyday Math and Science on Gabriel H. Brown</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/tags/everyday-math-and-science/</link><description>Recent content in Everyday Math and Science on Gabriel H. Brown</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright [Gabriel H. Brown](/).</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 18:37:01 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ghbrown.net/tags/everyday-math-and-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Expected profit for a 50/50 Raffle</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/50_50_raffle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 18:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/50_50_raffle/</guid><description>Expected profit for a 50/50 Raffle An auto race I recently attended also ran a 50/50 raffle, which is where a single winner receives 50% of the money collected from ticket sales.
Just like any form of gambling, it&amp;rsquo;s almost certainly a bad idea on average, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to figure out precisely how bad without a pencil and a bit of scratch paper (which I got the next morning).</description></item><item><title>The theoretical minimum time for competition speed climbing</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/speed_climbing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 18:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/speed_climbing/</guid><description>The theoretical minimum time for competition speed climbing After watching a short documentary on the state and progress of competition speed climbing, with times going ever lower and quotes like &amp;ldquo;we never though X time was possible, and now were not sure how low times will go&amp;rdquo; I was inspired to provide an answer in the form of a lower bound.
In this write up simple physics and physiological estimates are used calculate this lower bound.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Gimpy's Intellectifier</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/uncle_gimpy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 18:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/uncle_gimpy/</guid><description>Uncle Gimpy&amp;rsquo;s Intellectifier An old reference sheet with simple formulae for length, area, volume as well as useful conversions. It&amp;rsquo;s called Uncle Gimpy&amp;rsquo;s Intellectifier, and is meant to be folded up and kept in a wallet or purse. This is certainly from a time before internet enabled personal devices (probably at least the 1980s), but these sorts of reference sheets are still just as useful today, if not less common.</description></item><item><title>Calculating the number of atoms in the Sun</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/sun_atoms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 18:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/sun_atoms/</guid><description>Calculating the number of atoms in the Sun It is said Freeman Dyson attempted to complete this task at the age of 4 or 5.
In this write up we complete the calculation and simultaneously present the necessary basics of chemistry and measurement.</description></item></channel></rss>