<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About Me on Gabriel H. Brown</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in About Me on Gabriel H. Brown</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 21:32:55 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ghbrown.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Expected profit for a 50/50 Raffle</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/posts/50_50_raffle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 18:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/posts/50_50_raffle/</guid><description>Expected profit for a 50/50 Raffle An auto race I recently attended also ran a 50/50 raffle, which is where a single winner receives 50% of the money collected from ticket sales.
Just like any form of gambling, it&amp;rsquo;s almost certainly a bad idea on average, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to figure out precisely how bad without a pencil and a bit of scratch paper (which I got the next morning).</description></item><item><title>Behavior of conjugate gradient residual</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/posts/cg_residual/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 22:19:38 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/posts/cg_residual/</guid><description>Behavior of the conjugate gradient residual An often stressed property of the conjugate gradient method (CG) for solving linear systems is the monotonic decrease in the A-norm of the error. When CG is applied in practice the exact solution is unknown and the error cannot be computed or tracked, so the residual or relative residual is used instead.
However, the kinds of guarantees available for residuals are slightly weaker and more involved than is often presented, due to complications introduced by different norms and arithmetic precisions.</description></item><item><title>Linear Algebra Pronunciation Guide</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/posts/linear_algebra_pronunciation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 18:00:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/posts/linear_algebra_pronunciation/</guid><description>Linear Algebra Pronunciation Guide Like all fields of mathematics, linear algebra has many prominent figures whose names are non-trivial to pronounce in English (the lingua franca of science and mathematics).
This is further complicated by numerical linear algebra libraries which have inconsistent and unintuitive pronunciations.
Cholesky pronounced: ko - less - key (somewhat throaty ko, like kho) often mispronounced: chuh - less - key notes: this is somewhat muddled by that fact that Choleskly was paternally Polish and maternally French, and grew up in France, but I side with the Polish pronunciation (see references) Schur pronounced: shore often mispronounced: sherr (rhymes with her) Krylov pronounced: cree - lav, cree - luvf often mispronounced: cry - lawv BLAS pronounced: blawz (rhymes with paws), blaws (rhymes with gloss, perhaps slightly less common) often mispronounced: blass (rhymes with class) LAPACK pronounced: L - A - pack (syllabic rhyme with bell - may - pack) often mispronounced: luh - pack SCALAPACK pronounced: skay - luh - pack (syllabic rhyme with may - uh - pack) often mispronounced: anything else PETSC pronounced: pet - see often mispronounced: anything else References: Cholesky, BLAS and LAPACK, PETSc</description></item><item><title>Posts (chronological)</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/posts_timeline/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 22:48:16 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/posts_timeline/</guid><description>asdf asdf asdf
asdf</description></item><item><title>Timeline</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/posts/posts_timeline/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 22:48:16 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/posts/posts_timeline/</guid><description>All posts; ordered newest first.</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/research/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 12:45:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/research/</guid><description>RESEARCH RESEARCH POSITIONS As a first year student I plan to investigate research groups with a focus on numerical algorithms, including linear algebra and optimization. During my master&amp;rsquo;s degree I worked on computational electronic structure for multiscale modeling and coupled quantum Monte Carlo to total energy tight binding via the creation of bespoke parameterizations. I also spent a year working in tandem on theoretical and numerical aspects of the tensor eigenpair problem, including conditioning and clustering.</description></item><item><title>Hobbies and Interests</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/hobbies_and_interests/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:29:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/hobbies_and_interests/</guid><description>Hobbies &amp;amp; Interests Observational Astronomy Open these images in a new tab to get them at full size and resolution.
Single shot, unedited image of the Moon through small refractor telescope. Taken in Steinhatchee, FL on 2020/05/22. Single shot, edited image of Jupiter and its four Galilean moons at low magnification. The contrast between the background and moons was enhanced; the glare from Jupiter was reduced and it was recolored to more accurately represent the color seen with the eye that night.</description></item><item><title>Random</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/random/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:05:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/random/</guid><description>Random Prime Number Detector Input a number to determine if it is prime.
The maximum input value before truncation error is 9007199254740991 (~9e15, nine and fifteen zeros!), which is not prime but has a relatively large least factor. This is because JavaScript uses double-precision floating-point numbers according to IEEE 754, and this number is the largest this format supports.
Uncle Gimpy&amp;rsquo;s Intellectifier Here is an old reference sheet with simple formulae for length, area, volume as well as useful conversions.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/publications/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 23:53:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/publications/</guid><description>Publications 2022 M. J. Johnson. G.H. Brown, et al., &amp;ldquo;Two Atmospheric Pressure Plasma Jets Driven by Phase-Shifted Voltages: A Method to Control Plasma Properties at the Plasma–Surface Interface&amp;rdquo;, IEEE Transaction on Plasma Science, 2022. link 2021 N. Shaffer, G.H. Brown, et al., &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s new in the Fortran standard library?&amp;rdquo;, International Fortran Conference 2021, 2021. link H.E. Delgado, G.H. Brown, D.M. Bartels, P. Rumbach, and D. B. Go, &amp;ldquo;The scaling of kinetic and transport behaviors of a plasma-liquid interface&amp;rdquo;, Journal of Applied Physics, vol.</description></item><item><title>Traditional Chain Pizza Review</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/posts/traditional_chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 18:55:13 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/posts/traditional_chain/</guid><description>Hand Tossed / Traditional Pizza Review (Chain) A review of traditional style pizzas from national chains (specifically those in the Urbana, IL area) including: Domino&amp;rsquo;s, Jet&amp;rsquo;s, Little Ceasars, Papa John&amp;rsquo;s, and Pizza Hut.
Domino&amp;rsquo;s standard/traditional pizza (top left) has a slightly doughy base with a golden, crisp bottom. At the crust, the dough is crisp on the outside while remaining soft and well inflated on the inside (and covered with a tasty garlic butter).</description></item><item><title>Deep Dish Chain Pizza Review</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/posts/deep_dish_chain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 18:54:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/posts/deep_dish_chain/</guid><description>Deep Dish / Pan Pizza Review (Chain) A review of deep dish and pan style pizzas from national chains (specifically those in the Urbana, IL area) including: Domino&amp;rsquo;s, Jet&amp;rsquo;s, Little Ceasars, Papa John&amp;rsquo;s and Pizza Hut.
Domino&amp;rsquo;s pan pizza (top left) is appropriately doughy with a crisp bottom and a crust that was almost indiscernible from the rest of the pizza. However, the bread/dough was alarmingly sweet as compared to the typical pizza experience.</description></item></channel></rss>