<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About Me on Gabriel H. Brown</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/</link><description>Recent content in About Me on Gabriel H. Brown</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 21:32:55 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ghbrown.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A sufficient condition for non-negative solutions to non-negative linear systems</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/sufficient_nonnegative/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 19:19:38 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/sufficient_nonnegative/</guid><description>A sufficient condition for non-negative solutions to non-negative linear systems Here we are concerned with &amp;ldquo;non-negative&amp;rdquo; linear systems, that is, linear systems where $\mathbf{A}, \mathbf{b} \geq \mathbf{0}$ (elementwise). In particular, we give a sufficient condition for non-negativity of the solution $\mathbf{x}$ to $\mathbf{Ax} = \mathbf{b}$.
First, we discuss an intuition for the result. The columns of $\mathbf{A}$ form a linear cone; if a vector $\mathbf{c}$ (a right hand side to the linear system) is known to lie in the cone, then one can find a &amp;ldquo;subcone&amp;rdquo; containing $\mathbf{c}$.</description></item><item><title>The space of matrices where LU requires pivoting is almost full-dimensional</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/dim_lu_pivot_needed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 19:19:38 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/dim_lu_pivot_needed/</guid><description>The space of matrices requiring pivoted LU factorization is almost full-dimensional The pivoted LU factorization of square matrices is the key routine for the direct solution of linear systems. All square, invertible matrices have a pivoted LU factorization of the form $\mathbf{PA} = \mathbf{LU}$, where $\mathbf{P}$ is a permutation matrix and $\mathbf{L}, \; \mathbf{U}$ are respectively upper and lower triangular.
However, not all square, invertible matrices have a factorization of the form $\mathbf{A} = \mathbf{LU}$ (an LU factorization).</description></item><item><title>This website: thoughts and history</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/this_website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 18:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/this_website/</guid><description>This website History 2020-04: website started as a pandemic project after learning that GitHub offered free hosting, written in plain HTML, CSS, and Javascript (a great learning experience)
2022-10: website transitioned to Hugo, a massive boon to maintainability and flexibility
2023-01: bought and used the ghbrown.net domain name
Fun Facts On every refresh of this website the header color is changed according to the selection of a (pseudo)random number.
The site structure was originally inspired by and modeled after Matthew Zahr&amp;#39;s website.</description></item><item><title>LLVM will win the Turing Award</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/llvm_turing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 23:21:47 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/llvm_turing/</guid><description>LLVM will win the Turing Award (prediction) The LLVM Project, which focuses on &amp;ldquo;modular and reusable compiler technologies&amp;rdquo; has had an enormous impact on the field of compilers, and by extension almost every kind of &amp;ldquo;applied&amp;rdquo; computer science.
Though compilers (at the time of writing) is not my area of expertise, LLVM&amp;rsquo;s impact on my own field of &amp;ldquo;numerical computing&amp;rdquo; is undeniable. Examples include:
the compiler for the Chapel programming language the Flang and LFortran compilers for the Fortran programming language Intel&amp;rsquo;s IFX compiler for the Fortran programming language (it was the discovery that IFX was using LLVM that that spurred me to make this post) (Intel URLs are famous for breaking, apologies in advance) the compiler for the Julia programming language Needless to say, I strongly believe that one or both of Chris Lattner and Vikram Adve (the original authors of LLVM) will win the Turing Award for their work on LLVM.</description></item><item><title>Expected profit for a 50/50 Raffle</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/50_50_raffle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 18:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/50_50_raffle/</guid><description>Expected profit for a 50/50 Raffle An auto race I recently attended also ran a 50/50 raffle, which is where a single winner receives 50% of the money collected from ticket sales.
Just like any form of gambling, it&amp;rsquo;s almost certainly a bad idea on average, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to figure out precisely how bad without a pencil and a bit of scratch paper (which I got the next morning).</description></item><item><title>Behavior of conjugate gradient residual</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/cg_residual/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 22:19:38 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/cg_residual/</guid><description>Behavior of the conjugate gradient residual An often stressed property of the conjugate gradient method (CG) for solving linear systems is the monotonic decrease in the A-norm of the error. When CG is applied in practice the exact solution is unknown and the error cannot be computed or tracked, so the residual or relative residual is used instead.
However, the kinds of guarantees available for residuals are slightly weaker and more involved than is often presented, due to complications introduced by different norms and arithmetic precisions.</description></item><item><title>Linear Algebra Pronunciation Guide</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/linear_algebra_pronunciation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 18:00:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/linear_algebra_pronunciation/</guid><description>Linear Algebra Pronunciation Guide Like all fields of mathematics, linear algebra has many prominent figures whose names are non-trivial to pronounce in English (the lingua franca of science and mathematics).
This is further complicated by numerical linear algebra libraries which have inconsistent and unintuitive pronunciations.
Cholesky pronounced: ko - less - key (somewhat throaty ko, like kho) often mispronounced: chuh - less - key notes: this is somewhat muddled by that fact that Choleskly was paternally Polish and maternally French, and grew up in France, but I side with the Polish pronunciation (see references) Schur pronounced: shore often mispronounced: sherr (rhymes with her) Krylov pronounced: cree - lav, cree - luvf often mispronounced: cry - lawv BLAS pronounced: blawz (rhymes with paws), bloss (rhymes with gloss, perhaps slightly less common) often mispronounced: blass (rhymes with class) LAPACK pronounced: L - A - pack (syllabic rhyme with bell - may - pack) often mispronounced: luh - pack SCALAPACK pronounced: skay - luh - pack (syllabic rhyme with may - uh - pack) often mispronounced: anything else PETSC pronounced: pet - see often mispronounced: anything else References: Cholesky, BLAS and LAPACK, PETSc</description></item><item><title>Timeline</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/posts_timeline/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 22:48:16 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/posts_timeline/</guid><description>All posts; ordered newest first.</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/topics/research/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 12:45:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/topics/research/</guid><description>RESEARCH RESEARCH POSITIONS I am fortunate to be advised by Joe Kileel, with whom I am currently working on problems related to low rank tensor approximation. During my master&amp;rsquo;s degree I worked with Edgar Solomonik on theoretical and numerical aspects of the tensor eigenpair problem, and with Harley Johnson on computational electronic structure. As an undergraduate I researched multiple phenomena related to nonequilibrium plasmas - from dielectric barrier discharges to plasma jets, and from experimentation and instrumentation to computation.</description></item><item><title>Hobbies and Interests</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/topics/hobbies_and_interests/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:29:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/topics/hobbies_and_interests/</guid><description>Hobbies &amp;amp; Interests Observational Astronomy Open these images in a new tab to get them at full size and resolution.
Single shot, unedited image of the Moon through small refractor telescope. Taken in Steinhatchee, FL on 2020/05/22. Single shot, edited image of Jupiter and its four Galilean moons at low magnification. The contrast between the background and moons was enhanced; the glare from Jupiter was reduced and it was recolored to more accurately represent the color seen with the eye that night.</description></item><item><title>Open Source</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/topics/open_source/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:29:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/topics/open_source/</guid><description>(Free and) Open Source I believe in free and open source software (FOSS), so I dedicate a significant amount of time and effort to this end.
Here are some projects I&amp;rsquo;ve contributed to:
Chapel The Chapel programming language is designed for parallel computing at scale. I package the compiler for Arch Linux, and have contributed multiple routines to built in modules. fortran-lang fortran-lang is a community effort to polish and modernize the Fortran programming language.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/topics/publications/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 23:53:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/topics/publications/</guid><description>Publications 2022 M. J. Johnson. G.H. Brown, et al., &amp;ldquo;Two Atmospheric Pressure Plasma Jets Driven by Phase-Shifted Voltages: A Method to Control Plasma Properties at the Plasma–Surface Interface&amp;rdquo;, IEEE Transaction on Plasma Science, 2022. link 2021 N. Shaffer, G.H. Brown, et al., &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s new in the Fortran standard library?&amp;rdquo;, International Fortran Conference 2021, 2021. link H.E. Delgado, G.H. Brown, D.M. Bartels, P. Rumbach, and D. B. Go, &amp;ldquo;The scaling of kinetic and transport behaviors of a plasma-liquid interface&amp;rdquo;, Journal of Applied Physics, vol.</description></item><item><title>Interior eigenvectors of symmetric matrices are saddle points</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/symmetric_saddle_points/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 22:19:38 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/symmetric_saddle_points/</guid><description>Interior eigenvectors of symmetric matrices are saddle points Eigenpairs of symmetric matrices are intimately related to optimization and critical points, with the eigenvectors being critical points of the Rayleigh quotient. In optimization settings, the type of critical point (minimum, maximum, saddle point) is an important feature in designing and understanding algorithms.
This write up characterizes the nature of all critical points (eigenvectors), with the main result being that all interior eigenvectors are saddle points.</description></item><item><title>Relationship between power iteration and gradient descent</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/pow_iter_grad_desc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:19:38 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/pow_iter_grad_desc/</guid><description>The relationship between power iteration and gradient descent Although the majority of successful algorithms for the symmetric tensor eigenvalue problem use optimization techniques directly, there are a few notable algorithms that do not appear to be based on optimization. Rather, they more closely resemble power iteration and shifted power iteration.
In this write up we show that this is a false dichotomy, and that these methods are equivalent to very simple and classical optimization methods.</description></item><item><title>The theoretical minimum time for competition speed climbing</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/speed_climbing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 18:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/speed_climbing/</guid><description>The theoretical minimum time for competition speed climbing After watching a short documentary on the state and progress of competition speed climbing, with times going ever lower and quotes like &amp;ldquo;we never though X time was possible, and now were not sure how low times will go&amp;rdquo; I was inspired to provide an answer in the form of a lower bound.
In this write up simple physics and physiological estimates are used calculate this lower bound.</description></item><item><title>Traditional Chain Pizza Review</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/traditional_chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 18:55:13 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/traditional_chain/</guid><description>Hand Tossed / Traditional Pizza Review (Chain) A review of traditional style pizzas from national chains (specifically those in the Urbana, IL area) including: Domino&amp;rsquo;s, Jet&amp;rsquo;s, Little Ceasars, Papa John&amp;rsquo;s, and Pizza Hut.
Domino&amp;rsquo;s standard/traditional pizza (top left) has a slightly doughy base with a golden, crisp bottom. At the crust, the dough is crisp on the outside while remaining soft and well inflated on the inside (and covered with a tasty garlic butter).</description></item><item><title>Deep Dish Chain Pizza Review</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/deep_dish_chain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 18:54:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/deep_dish_chain/</guid><description>Deep Dish / Pan Pizza Review (Chain) A review of deep dish and pan style pizzas from national chains (specifically those in the Urbana, IL area) including: Domino&amp;rsquo;s, Jet&amp;rsquo;s, Little Ceasars, Papa John&amp;rsquo;s and Pizza Hut.
Domino&amp;rsquo;s pan pizza (top left) is appropriately doughy with a crisp bottom and a crust that was almost indiscernible from the rest of the pizza. However, the bread/dough was alarmingly sweet as compared to the typical pizza experience.</description></item><item><title>An alternative method to compute Gauss's sum</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/gauss_sum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 18:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/gauss_sum/</guid><description>An alternative method to compute Guass&amp;rsquo;s sum (from 1 to n) Gauss famously (and possibly fictionally) computed the sum between 1 and 100 at a young age. His original logic relies on symmetry and geometrical thought, especially triangles.
In this write up we provide an alternative derivation of the same result, but using a technique more reminiscent of strategies for solving ordinary differential equations.</description></item><item><title>Uncle Gimpy's Intellectifier</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/uncle_gimpy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 18:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/uncle_gimpy/</guid><description>Uncle Gimpy&amp;rsquo;s Intellectifier An old reference sheet with simple formulae for length, area, volume as well as useful conversions. It&amp;rsquo;s called Uncle Gimpy&amp;rsquo;s Intellectifier, and is meant to be folded up and kept in a wallet or purse. This is certainly from a time before internet enabled personal devices (probably at least the 1980s), but these sorts of reference sheets are still just as useful today, if not less common.</description></item><item><title>Prime number detector</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/prime_detector/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 18:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/prime_detector/</guid><description>Prime Number Detector Input a number to determine if it is prime.
The maximum input value before truncation error is 9007199254740991 (~9e15, nine and fifteen zeros!), which is not prime but has a relatively large least factor. This is because JavaScript uses double-precision floating-point numbers according to IEEE 754, and this number is the largest this format supports.
Notes I used this little project to get my feet wet with Javascript when I was building my website from raw HTML and CSS.</description></item><item><title>Re() and Im() as complex numbers</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/re_im_as_numbers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 18:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/re_im_as_numbers/</guid><description>Re() and Im() as complex numbers A summer day in 2019 reading Complex Variables and Applications by Churchill inspired what I now realize is almost certainly a useless (but perhaps slightly amusing) result. Enjoy.</description></item><item><title>Calculating the number of atoms in the Sun</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/sun_atoms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 18:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/sun_atoms/</guid><description>Calculating the number of atoms in the Sun It is said Freeman Dyson attempted to complete this task at the age of 4 or 5.
In this write up we complete the calculation and simultaneously present the necessary basics of chemistry and measurement.</description></item></channel></rss>