<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Topics on Gabriel H. Brown</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/topics/</link><description>Recent content in Topics on Gabriel H. Brown</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright [Gabriel H. Brown](/).</copyright><atom:link href="https://ghbrown.net/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hobbies and Interests</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/topics/hobbies_and_interests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/topics/hobbies_and_interests/</guid><description>Hobbies &amp;amp; Interests Observational Astronomy Open these images in a new tab to get them at full size and resolution.
Single shot, unedited image of the Moon through small refractor telescope. Taken in Steinhatchee, FL on 2020/05/22. Single shot, edited image of Jupiter and its four Galilean moons at low magnification. The contrast between the background and moons was enhanced; the glare from Jupiter was reduced and it was recolored to more accurately represent the color seen with the eye that night.</description></item><item><title>Open Source</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/topics/open_source/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/topics/open_source/</guid><description>(Free and) Open Source I believe in free and open source software (FOSS), so I dedicate a significant amount of time and effort to this end.
Here are some projects I&amp;rsquo;ve contributed to:
Chapel The Chapel programming language is designed for parallel computing at scale. I package the compiler for Arch Linux, and have contributed multiple routines to built in modules. fortran-lang fortran-lang is a community effort to polish and modernize the Fortran programming language.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/topics/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/topics/publications/</guid><description>Publications 2022 M. J. Johnson. G.H. Brown, et al., &amp;ldquo;Two Atmospheric Pressure Plasma Jets Driven by Phase-Shifted Voltages: A Method to Control Plasma Properties at the Plasma–Surface Interface&amp;rdquo;, IEEE Transaction on Plasma Science, 2022. link 2021 N. Shaffer, G.H. Brown, et al., &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s new in the Fortran standard library?&amp;rdquo;, International Fortran Conference 2021, 2021. link H.E. Delgado, G.H. Brown, D.M. Bartels, P. Rumbach, and D. B. Go, &amp;ldquo;The scaling of kinetic and transport behaviors of a plasma-liquid interface&amp;rdquo;, Journal of Applied Physics, vol.</description></item><item><title>Quotes</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/topics/quotes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/topics/quotes/</guid><description>Quotes Congratulations if you found this page!
It&amp;rsquo;s not linked anywhere on my site but is the source page from which the random quotes are drawn.
MC: Gucchon, you win or you lose?
Gucchon: I don&amp;rsquo;t care. &amp;ldquo;So we want to make it easy to write parallel programs&amp;hellip;
We can&amp;rsquo;t, writing parallel programs is extremely difficult.&amp;rdquo; - Joe Armstrong &amp;ldquo;7 iterations is a good number.&amp;rdquo; - numerical analysis student
&amp;ldquo;Nothing brings fear to my heart more than a floating point number.</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/topics/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/topics/research/</guid><description>Research Research Positions I am fortunate to be advised by Joe Kileel, with whom I am currently working on problems related to low rank tensor approximation. During my master&amp;rsquo;s degree I worked with Edgar Solomonik on theoretical and numerical aspects of the tensor eigenpair problem, and with Harley Johnson on computational electronic structure. As an undergraduate I researched multiple phenomena related to nonequilibrium plasmas including plasma-liquid simulations with David Go and plasma jets with Scott Walton.</description></item></channel></rss>