<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Topics on Gabriel H. Brown</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/</link><description>Recent content in Topics on Gabriel H. Brown</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 22:48:16 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Posts (chronological)</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/posts_timeline/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 22:48:16 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/posts_timeline/</guid><description>asdf asdf asdf
asdf</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/research/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 12:45:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/research/</guid><description>RESEARCH RESEARCH POSITIONS As a first year student I plan to investigate research groups with a focus on numerical algorithms, including linear algebra and optimization. During my master&amp;rsquo;s degree I worked on computational electronic structure for multiscale modeling and coupled quantum Monte Carlo to total energy tight binding via the creation of bespoke parameterizations. I also spent a year working in tandem on theoretical and numerical aspects of the tensor eigenpair problem, including conditioning and clustering.</description></item><item><title>Hobbies and Interests</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/hobbies_and_interests/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:29:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/hobbies_and_interests/</guid><description>Hobbies &amp;amp; Interests Observational Astronomy Open these images in a new tab to get them at full size and resolution.
Single shot, unedited image of the Moon through small refractor telescope. Taken in Steinhatchee, FL on 2020/05/22. Single shot, edited image of Jupiter and its four Galilean moons at low magnification. The contrast between the background and moons was enhanced; the glare from Jupiter was reduced and it was recolored to more accurately represent the color seen with the eye that night.</description></item><item><title>Random</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/random/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:05:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/random/</guid><description>Random Prime Number Detector Input a number to determine if it is prime.
The maximum input value before truncation error is 9007199254740991 (~9e15, nine and fifteen zeros!), which is not prime but has a relatively large least factor. This is because JavaScript uses double-precision floating-point numbers according to IEEE 754, and this number is the largest this format supports.
Uncle Gimpy&amp;rsquo;s Intellectifier Here is an old reference sheet with simple formulae for length, area, volume as well as useful conversions.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/publications/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 23:53:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.github.io/topics/publications/</guid><description>Publications 2022 M. J. Johnson. G.H. Brown, et al., &amp;ldquo;Two Atmospheric Pressure Plasma Jets Driven by Phase-Shifted Voltages: A Method to Control Plasma Properties at the Plasma–Surface Interface&amp;rdquo;, IEEE Transaction on Plasma Science, 2022. link 2021 N. Shaffer, G.H. Brown, et al., &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s new in the Fortran standard library?&amp;rdquo;, International Fortran Conference 2021, 2021. link H.E. Delgado, G.H. Brown, D.M. Bartels, P. Rumbach, and D. B. Go, &amp;ldquo;The scaling of kinetic and transport behaviors of a plasma-liquid interface&amp;rdquo;, Journal of Applied Physics, vol.</description></item></channel></rss>