<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Food on Gabriel H. Brown</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/tags/food/</link><description>Recent content in Food on Gabriel H. Brown</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright [Gabriel H. Brown](/).</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 12:19:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ghbrown.net/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prometheus and Lasagna</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/lasagna/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 12:19:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/lasagna/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prometheus-and-lasagna">Prometheus and Lasagna&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>After hundreds of thousands of years of the species &lt;em>homo sapiens&lt;/em>, it&amp;rsquo;s truly amazing to be the first person to achieve, create, or experience something.
Maybe someday I&amp;rsquo;ll create an algorithm or prove a theorem which will change the world.
Perhaps one day I&amp;rsquo;ll steal just a bit of knowledge from the gods, and then give it to the world.
However, Aug. 13, 2024 was not to be such a day for me, at least not as such.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Traditional Chain Pizza Review</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/traditional_chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 18:55:13 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/traditional_chain/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="hand-tossed--traditional-pizza-review-chain">Hand Tossed / Traditional Pizza Review (Chain)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A review of traditional style pizzas from national chains (specifically those in the Urbana, IL area) including: Domino&amp;rsquo;s, Jet&amp;rsquo;s, Little Ceasars, Papa John&amp;rsquo;s, and Pizza Hut.&lt;/p>
&lt;table style="width:100%">
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>
 &lt;img src="https://ghbrown.net/assets/posts/traditional_chain/TraditionalChain.jpg">
 &lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;span class="themecolor">Domino&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/span> standard/traditional pizza (top left) has a slightly doughy base with a golden, crisp bottom.
At the crust, the dough is crisp on the outside while remaining soft and well inflated on the inside (and covered with a tasty garlic butter).
sauce is well distributed and in a good ratio with the other components.
Its flavor was light on spices and pleasantly acidic.
propietary blend of cheeses (equal parts monterey jack, mozzarella, white cheddar) and the carefully metered cook time means the cheese is both flavorful (properly browned) and tender (not overcooked).
This contributes to the overall &amp;ldquo;tender bite&amp;rdquo; of the pizza; that is to say the selected bite separates from the rest of the slice with no gnawing or vigorous head shaking.
&lt;br>
[COST: $8.49 after tax for 13 inch large.]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deep Dish Chain Pizza Review</title><link>https://ghbrown.net/posts/deep_dish_chain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 18:54:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ghbrown.net/posts/deep_dish_chain/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="deep-dish--pan-pizza-review-chain">Deep Dish / Pan Pizza Review (Chain)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A review of deep dish and pan style pizzas from national chains (specifically those in the Urbana, IL area) including: Domino&amp;rsquo;s, Jet&amp;rsquo;s, Little Ceasars, Papa John&amp;rsquo;s and Pizza Hut.&lt;/p>
&lt;table style="width:100%">
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>
 &lt;img src="https://ghbrown.net/assets/posts/deep_dish_chain/DeepDishPanChain.jpg">
 &lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;span class="themecolor">Domino&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/span> pan pizza (top left) is appropriately doughy with a crisp bottom and a crust that was almost indiscernible from the rest of the pizza.
However, the bread/dough was alarmingly sweet as compared to the typical pizza experience.
The sauce was well distributed on the pizza, but the ratio of sauce to the rest of the pizza was too low.
However, it is perhaps important to note that I err on the side of more sauce when in doubt.
As for taste, the sauce was appropriately acidic, but perhaps under spiced.
Moving up to cheese, it was applied in the correct proportion all the way to the edges, where crisped cheese bits could be had.
Notably, Domino&amp;rsquo;s blend of mozzarella, monterey jack, and white cheddar provides a punchier flavor when compared to 100% mozzarella topped pizzas.
&lt;br>
[COST: $10.68 after tax for 14 inch large.]&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>